DIPESH PANDEY

I have more than 2 years of professional experience working as a software engineer in startups across Asia and Europe. Currently, looking for beginner level opportunities in blockchain programming and data analytics. I am a fast learner, driven individual and always eager to work in innovative companies

Professional experience

Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Remote

Backend Developer(Part-time)

frontend developer

June/2021 - Present

 As an independent contractor, overseeing the MVP development of a cryptocurrency related SaaS platform

cryptocurrency related SaaS platform

Handling all tasks related to API development for the product, collaborating with the

Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Gjøvik, Norway

Research Assistant(Part-time)

Jan/2021 - Present

- · Work on hands-on programming of humanoid robots for school children
- Research the state-of-the-art methods used in the human robot interaction field and publish papers on the same

Teamcoda Remote

Freelance Developer (Part-time)

Sep/2019 - Dec/2020

- Worked as a backend developer with emphasis on API development, data analysis, with some time dedicated to frontend
- Built applications using serverless and microservice architectures especially focusing on cloud technologies like AWS and GCP

Teamcoda Remote

Freelance Developer (Part-time)

Sep/2019 - Dec/2020

- Worked as a backend developer with emphasis on API development, data analysis, with some time dedicated to frontend
- Built applications using serverless and microservice architectures especially focusing on cloud technologies like AWS and GCP

MyriadX - Full Identity Resolution

Singapore

Developer(Remote based in Nepal)

Mar/2018 - Oct/2020

- Worked with massive datasets mainly related to user activities on several websites
 of the clients. Included collection and transformation of data from few big clients in
 APAC
- Involvement in full-stack development in several projects using tools like Angular, Firebase, ExpressJS, Django, Python, Flask, Pandas, NumPy, PyTorch
- As the first hire of the Nepal team, helped increase the team size to 6 and managed communication with the parent team in Singapore

MyriadX - Full Identity Resolution

Singapore

Developer(Remote based in Nepal)

Mar/2018 - Oct/2020

- Worked with massive datasets mainly related to user activities on several websites
 of the clients. Included collection and transformation of data from few big clients in
 APAC
- Involvement in full-stack development in several projects using tools like Angular, Firebase, ExpressJS, Django, Python, Flask, Pandas, NumPy, PyTorch
- As the first hire of the Nepal team, helped increase the team size to 6 and managed communication with the parent team in Singapore

Education

Masters in Applied Computer Science

Gjøvik, Norway

Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Aug/2020 - Present

• Taking courses ranging from web and mobile technologies to deeplearning with the specialization on blockchain technologies

Technical Skills

Programming Python, Javascript, **Languages:** Typescript

Machine learning: NLTK, PyTorch,

Gensim, Spacy

Web: Angular, Django, Flask, NodeJS, NestJS, Ionic, Flutter

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL,

MongoDB, Firebase

Cloud Services: AWS, GCP

Extra: Selenium, PhantomJS, BeautifulSoup, Scrapy, Puppeteer

Participations

Refinitiv Summits 2019, Singapore Provided on-site development support during the summit held in Singapore consisting of 500+ participants

Yomari Code Camp - 2017
- Participated as well as organized a code camp where teams were to come up with innovative product ideas and present it to the organizers

Certifications

Neural Networks and Deep Learning(Online Course by deeplearning.ai) - Learned the basics of deep learning, as well as learned to create my own neural network from scratch

Data Science for Business Innovation(Online course by EIT Digital and Politecnico di Milano) -Learned how data science is used in business applications

Bachelors in Computer Engineering

Institute of Engineering, Tribhuvan University

Lalitpur, Nepal Nov/2013 - Sep/2017

Projects

BetBot, 2021 (https://betbot.at)

- A platform where sports betting tips are collected from several sources and filtered using several algorithms to optimize the chances of winning in a given bet
- Worked as an independent contractor to create a SaaS system for a client

Interactive Event/Conference, 2020

(https://crunchevent.com)

- A Web application delivering interactive experience during events including answer queries, voting screens, automated report generation

ResumeRank, 2019

- Created dataset from scratch to train a neural network that predicts the section of a CV like Qualification, Skills, and Experience
- Created a custom, deployed solution for a client that had around 5000 CVs